Castle Arcantez
A toast to our alliance
The Intention of the Seitz Army
and your ascendance to the
governorship of Seitz Province.
Governor of Seitz
Grenda Domatheson
I'm still getting used to the title.
I'm grateful you're willing to work
with us, unlike your predecessor.
Vasmarque Salamakhia
We seek good relations with the
future governor of Missian.
Our interests are aligned.
I pledge on the honor of Seitz
to work with you.
My hope is to isolate Canarre
from the main force.
Canarre has too much power
for a single district.
I want you to lock them down.
My right hand, Borotz.
Borotz Heygand
He was my commander
during the insurrection.
It is an honor to meet you.
He'll lead the upcoming
invasion of Canarre, as well.
We intend to send 80,000 soldiers.
Impressive dedication.
That's ten times Canarre's army.
There's something in Canarre
I'm quite eager to obtain.
And so, in exchange for victory,
you want food, resources,
and all spoils from
the invasion of Canarre?
Yes, if you please.
Is it their troops you're after?
I'll be going now.
I'd like to begin
preparations immediately.
If you don't mind, I've been curious...
What do you seek to accomplish
by becoming governor of Missian?
Independence?
Couran is a sad man, incapable of trust.
Even if he is family.
I want to protect our land
and people as my father did.
That is all.
Don't worry. We'll take down Canarre.
You can focus on settling accounts
between you and your brother.
Borotz, round up soldiers
from all regions of Seitz.
If I may, Governor...
This conquest in Canarre
is pointless for us.
It will not win us much in the
way of territory or provisions.
Especially right after the insurrection...
Should you not have asked for more?
Borotz.
Are you aware of a man named Ars Louvent?
The current headman
of Canarre? What of him?
He's but thirteen years old.
Don't you find that strange?
I've heard he has a curious ability
to perceive the talents of others.
Perceive their talents?
I looked into it, and he does have a
number of extremely talented retainers.
I want to occupy Canarre and
take Ars Louvent for myself!
I also value you as my right hand.
I'm counting on you.
Ars Louvent...
Just what kind of man is he?
Episode 26   Canarre in Crisis
I'll read the message Krall has sent us.
"Seitz is mustering 80,000 soldiers
on the border with Missian.
We request urgent action."
Eighty thousand? Can that really be true?
That's ten times what Canarre has!
If it is true, Coumeire's forces alone
won't be enough to halt their advance.
But why is Seitz being so aggressive?
They had their own civil war
not long ago, didn't they?
Yes.
We signed a secret peace treaty
with Seitz during the war.
But it appears the former governor's
retainers staged a coup and overthrew him.
Which means that treaty is null and void.
But why now, I wonder?
They're only just recovering,
so things must be still chaotic.
I don't like it.
Your forces are set to rendezvous
with Couran's, right?
Yes.
I don't get the feeling
Seitz is being strong-armed.
Someone behind the scenes has a plan.
Sorry I'm late.
Pham!
What did you see of Seitz's army?
In a word...
It's bad. I've never seen
a camp that large.
And their commander is excellent.
In the insurrection, they took out
a force of 100,000 with half that.
Also...
Is that a flame magistone?
Don't tell me...
Indeed, you can't mine flame
magistones in Seitz.
That gave me a hunch, so I looked into it,
and I was right.
While Seitz is marching on us, Vasmarque
will be sending soldiers to Verzud.
Sounds like Vasmarque's signed an alliance
with the new governor of Seitz.
What, is that bad?
Lord Couran won't be able to send aid.
We'll have to fight Seitz's 80,000 troops
with what we have on hand.
H-How are Canarre's defenses?
Though we'll naturally have
the advantage defending,
Canarre's infrastructure isn't excellent.
We can hold out... a year, I'd expect.
Canarre's going to fall at this rate.
What do I do?
Betrayal's always an option.
Obviously, if we surrender,
the enemy will occupy Canarre.
But it might at least save your life.
With your Appraisal power,
you can still make your way,
which may save your retainers, as well.
Unacceptable.
Canarre is the land
Lord Couran entrusted to me.
I inherited it from Lord Lumeire.
And most of all, this is the
land my father protected.
The reason I serve here as lord
is to defend my homeland.
It would be all too easy
to hand this place over.
But what if the enemy pillages,
ravages, and makes my people suffer?
Everything I've done so far
has been to prevent that.
That is the one option I will not accept.
For me and the people who have
protected Canarre all this time...
This is a battle we can't afford to lose!
I thought you might say that.
It looks like the enemy will
make their move in a few weeks.
Put out a meeting call
to the lords of Canarre.
In one week, we'll make
for Coumeire Domain.
Yes, sir!
The new House Louvent has
only existed a few months...
and we're already being tested!
One Week Later
Lord Ars!
Word from Lord Couran!
And...
I understand your situation.
The defense of Canarre
is crucial to all of us.
You'll be facing a harder battle
than any you've faced before,
but I believe you and your
people can overcome it.
Perhaps I'm being overprotective,
but I've sent a few soldiers your way.
Put them to good use.
Twenty thousand reinforcements
from Lord Couran!
Amazing!
Clamant!
The Maitraw company!
What a boon they will be!
But Lord Couran has his own battle
against Lord Vasmarque to fight...
Ars!
Hammond Pleide,
lord of Torbequista Domain,
has come to aid Canarre
in its hour of need!
Hammond!
And...
I brought the boys, kiddo.
They were all raring to go.
Wouldn't stop asking.
Deputy lord of Lamburg, Mireille Grangeon,
has arrived to serve her lord.
You're not the only one who
thinks this battle is crucial!
Yes!
Everyone!
I'm glad to have you!
Let's hear it, Rosell.
How do you take down an army of
80,000 with a mere 28,000 troops?
We don't need to take them down.
What do you mean?
Their forces have just come
off a prolonged conflict.
Their soldiers aren't likely
to be at their best.
Plus, this invasion is
a conquest for them.
It's not existential like
their civil war was.
In other words, their morale will be low!
The only reason they would
ally with Lord Vasmarque
is because they think there's something
to be gained by invading us.
So we need to convince
them that this isn't true.
What we should focus on
isn't beating 80,000 foes.
It's using our 28,000
troops the right way
to make Seitz think they'll lose
more than they have to gain
so that they give up!
For better or worse,
this isn't a simple math equation.
That's what's interesting
about combat, right?
So this isn't a fight to defeat the
enemy, but to break their spirit!
Not least of all for Couran,
who sent us backup...
Let's give this our best, everyone!
Wow!
It fits perfectly and everything!
Yes.
I won't be able to stay by your
side during this operation.
But that armor will surely
protect you in my stead.
Thank you!
Lord Ars!
I have something for you, as well.
What are you doing, Licia?!
I'm cleansing you with
rulla leaves and petals.
It's an old Torbequistan good luck ritual.
They say if you then embrace the subject
like so, it guarantees their safe return.
I believe the Torbequistan
custom only requires water...
R-Regardless...
I'll look after Canarre in
your absence, Lord Ars.
I'll see you again soon.
The battlefield will be the Coumeire
River between Missian and Seitz.
We collapsed all the bridges,
so the enemy will likely cross here.
It's where the river is narrow
and relatively shallow.
It's the only place 80,000
soldiers could ford it.
Our main force of 20,000 has already
met up with Coumeire's army.
They'll establish camp along the river
to hold off the enemy vanguard.
The rest will provide assistance
from Coumeire Fortress,
including intercepting any forces
coming the long way around.
I'll entrust command of
the main force to you, Rietz.
The Night Before the Battle
You've done a fantastic job
holding them off so far.
Well, I know how to handle
a defensive battle.
But the real thing's soon to come.
We have the terrain advantage.
You've composed an
excellent plan, as well.
Tomorrow, we'll reach the Coumeire River.
Everyone, rest well so
you'll be ready for combat!
There's no way I can rest
before my first real battle.
When we arrive at the battlefield,
we'll check our equipment, and then...
It's addressed to you.
Th-Thank you.
What made you decide
to serve a lord?!
Why would you ask that?
It's not like it's a big deal.
But you're a dang celebrity, man!
You led the shock troops of
the famous Riven company!
I can't believe you're with us!
Is there some big dream you're chasing?!
Money, I guess.
Money?
I just thought serving a noble would
be a good way to make money.
Right...
Hey, you guys! You won't get much
sleep once the battle starts.
Anyway, I'm gonna head to bed.
Charlotte's amazing.
It's like nothing fazes her.
Charlotte's always been that way.
She's made of sterner stuff than us!
Musia, I truly worry for you, my daughter.
You're simply not cut out for battle.
You're clumsy, just like I am.
You have beautiful hair and fine features,
so I know you could find a good husband.
Leave the fighting to the men
and come home. I beg you.
I have to sleep.
Fear
Charlotte?
Oh, it's just you, Musia. You startled me.
You're still awake?
Just maintaining my weapon for tomorrow.
I always do this stuff before a battle.
I don't want messed-up gear
holding back my true power, y'know?
I'll be turning in soon,
so make sure you do the same.
Don't wanna collapse
on your first deployment.
Right...
Charlotte, don't you fear battle?
I... I left my village hoping
to be useful to someone...
I've worked hard in my training, too.
But... I'm afraid.
How can I stop feeling scared?
I'm scared, too.
Huh? But...
Oh, I'm not afraid of dying.
Like hell am I getting defeated.
But I've spent a long time on the
battlefield. I've killed a lot of people.
I've lived a good life.
I'd have no regrets if I fell.
The thing I'm a lot more afraid of...
is betraying Ars's faith in me.
I've always been focused on myself...
on changing myself,
on having more confidence...
But she's different.
That's why she's so strong.
Excuse me.
Can I join you?
Hell yeah. I'll teach you.
I hope I can be like her someday.
It's like he's sawing logs...
You have to do something, Zaht!
We'll never be able to sleep like this!
Captain, you gotta quiet down—
Big Bro...
Dad...
He's never gonna sleep soundly
clutching that thing.
I'll deal with it.
We won't hear him like this.
What? We totally still can!
C'mon, get to bed.
But those were our blankets!
Yeah!
Coumeire River
Enemy General
Lantorque Lodder
For Lord Borotz!
Charge!
We keep them from crossing.
That is our mission!
Bring victory to Canarre—to Lord Ars!
Long-range unit at the ready!
Loose arrows!
Trebuchet unit, advance!
Release!
Magic unit, barrier spells!
Vanguard, advance!
Long-range unit, target their infantry!
They're blocking our attacks with magic!
So be it! Don't let up!
Charlotte, Musia...
We're counting on you.
Looks like they've warmed
things up for us.
Time to get to work.
Musia's Determination
Sorry to put pressure on you,
but this all comes down to us.
You ready?
Yes!
It's okay.
My comrades' lives are riding on this.
It'll be okay!
I was just a normal village
girl a few months ago...
I can do this!
I don't know what I can do...
But...
I know that I can do it!
Forma...
I-I can't...
Someone made a mistake somewhere.
I've been incompetent my whole life.
So I...
I believe in you, Musia.
You have all the power you need.
Ars said so, so I know it's true.
Have faith.
I want to be like you, Charlotte!
Um, give me a knife, please!
I've never believed in myself before.
But I want to believe in myself someday.
I want to become strong enough that I can.
So...
For now, I'll believe in Charlotte,
who believes in me!
Forma Terra Akos Magnus!
What the...
The water...
Long-range unit, loose!
Forma Igni Erupt!
Now's our chance! Charge as fast as you can!
All right, it's our turn!
Zaht! Keep up, okay?!
Don't rush too far ahead!
Wh-What's going on here?
R-Retreat!
Nice work.
Thank you!
Well, Rietz? My Musia's
pretty awesome, huh?!
Indeed. And she's a nice girl,
unlike someone I know.
Hey, I'm a nice girl, too!
But enough talk.
It looks like they're up next.
Next time: "Zaht and Braham."
Next Time   Zaht and Braham